杰森 · 兰斯托夫: 一旦我们建立了网站,
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: Once
we've got our site set up,
我们要做的第一件事。
the first thing that we need to do.
是让我们的主题设置和运行所谓的预引导程序。
Is get our theme set up and running
with what's called a Pre-Bootstrap.
所以我们要确保我们要使用的文件夹存在,
So we wanna make sure that any
folders that we're gonna use, exist,
否则我们会得到一个错误。
because otherwise we'll get an error.
所以如果我们要设置一个主题,
So if we're setting up a theme,
通常来说，这个主题是要寻找数据。
typically speaking that theme
is gonna look for Data.
举个例子，我们的文档主题的工作方式
And for example, the way our Docs theme is
gonna work, is it's gonna be looking for
一个装满 MDX 文件的文件夹。
a folder full of MDX files.
因此，如果你把这个主题安装到一个网站，你不知道这一点
So if you install this theme into
a site and you don't know that and
你不能手动创建文件夹。
you don't manually create that folder.
默认情况下，我们会得到一个错误说，无法找到目录，无论如何。
By default we would get an error that
says, couldn't find directory, whatever.
所以我们要去检查一下,
So we're just gonna go ahead and
check for that,
在启动前确认目录是否存在。
make sure the directory
exists before we boot up.
为了避免任何令人困惑的错误，只需将该工作保存为
To avoid any of those confusing errors and
just save that work for
使用这个主题的人。
the people using the theme.
为了做到这一点，我们将进入我们的主题
To do that we're going
to go into our theme and
我们要创建一个叫做盖茨比节点的文件。
we're gonna create a file
called gatsby-node.
这使我们可以在构建过程中访问 Gatsby 生命周期方法,
This gives us access to the Gatsby
lifecycle methods during the build,
我们可以在这里做很多有趣的事。
we can do a whole bunch of fun stuff here.
我们需要做的是，我们要使用一个图书馆或者
And what we need to do here is,
we're going to use a library or
一个叫做 onPreBootstrap 的节点挂钩。
a node-hook called onPreBootstrap.
这让我们进入了盖茨比 API。
And this lets us get into the Gatsby API.
在里面我们要去盖茨比商店,
And inside of it,
we are going to use the Gatsby store,
这只是一些关于运行程序的信息。
which is just some information
about the running program.
然后我们要使用主题选项,
And then we're gonna
use the theme options,
这是大多数 API 钩子的第二个参数。
which come in as the second
argument to most API hooks.
在这里面，我们要把这个程序从商店的州里弄出来。
Inside of this, we're gonna get
the program out of the store's State.
这有点像是盖茨比内心深处的想法。
Now this is kind of like
a deep Gatsby internal.
基本上就是说，走进盖茨比商店
It's basically saying,
go into Gatsby store and
找出盖茨比认为它在哪里。
figure out where Gatsby believes it is.
你也可以通过美国工作目录协会或者美国国家航空航天管理局获得。
Which you could also get with the or
the current directory.
但这样做只会帮助控制,
But doing it this way just helps control,
这样无论你在哪里，盖茨比的环境都是一致的。
so that the Gatsby environment will be
consistent no matter where you are.
然后我们需要得到一些默认值
Then we need to get some defaults, so
我们得确保选项都设好了。
we need to make sure that
the options are always set.
所以如果这是空的，我们不希望它作为一个空对象返回,
So if this is empty, we don't want
that to come back as an empty object,
因为我们会得到错误。
because we'll get errors.
所以我们需要有默认值的选项。
So we need to get options with defaults.
在我们得到默认选项之后,
And then after we've got
the options with defaults,
我们需要找出内容路径。
we need to figure out the content path.
然后，一旦我们知道了这一点，我们需要检查是否目录
And then once we know that,
we need to check if directory
不存在 Jason Lengstorf: 我们需要创建它。
doesn't exist
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: We need to create it.
所以我们要做的第一件事,
So the first thing we need to do,
写一个效用函数来得到这些默认值。
is write a little utility
function to get these defaults.
所以对于如何做到这一点并没有一个严格的规则，但是
So there's not really a hard-and-fast
rule on how to do this, but
我要创建一个 utils 文件夹。
I'm just gonna create a utils folder.
在其中，我将创建 default-options. js,
And inside of it,
I'm gonna create default-options.js,
用我最喜欢的捷径。
using my favorite little shortcut.
如果你输入一个带斜杠的文件路径,
Which is that if you just type out
a file path with a slash in it,
它会为你创建那个文件夹。
it'll create that folder for you.
在这里面，我要导出一个函数。
And inside of this,
I'm going to export a function.
我们要在这里设置我们的选项
And we're gonna set up our options here,
so
我们的 basePath 将默认为只有根。
our basePath is gonna
default to just the root.
路径就是 URL 将会是什么，所以当我们创建页面时,
The path is what the URL will be,
so when we create pages,
我们要在网站的根部默认创建这些。
we're gonna create these at
the root of the site by default.
如果人们希望它在其他地方生活，我们将允许他们推翻这一规定。
And we'll allow people to override that
if they want it to live somewhere else.
然后我们要设置内容路径。
Then we're gonna set up the contentPath.
因此，默认情况下，我们要寻找
So by default, we're gonna look for
在网站的根部有一个文件夹，叫做 docs，内容就在里面。
a folder at the root of the site called
docs, and the content would live in there.
同样，我们会让人们推翻这一观点。
And again, we'll let people override that.
然后由于 MDX 工作方式的一个怪癖,
And then because of a quirk
with the way that MDX works,
我们需要知道该网站是否已经在使用 MDX。
we need to know whether or
not the site is already using MDX.
因为我们一次只能运行它的一个实例。
Because we can only have one
instance of it running at a time.
所以我将使用 externalmdx，默认情况下
So I'm going to useExternalMDX and
by default
我们假设该站点没有使用 MDX，我们将自己安装它。
we'll assume that the site is not using
MDX, and we will install it ourselves.
然后，因为我们只是输入了一个选项对象
And then, because we're just
feeding in an options object and
在这里设置 destructuring 的默认值。
setting the defaults in
this destructuring here.
我可以直接退回去。
I can just return these straight up.
所以我们将使用 basePath、 contentPath 和
So we'll do basePath, contentPath and
使用 externalmdx，这就是我们的 withDefaults 函数。
useExternalMDX and
that's our withDefaults function.
演讲者2: 应该是单数模块吗？
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Should
that be module singular?
杰森 · 兰斯托夫: 当然,
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: Sure should,
好捕捉，那将是有趣的调试[笑]。
good catch,
that would have been fun to debug [LAUGH].
是的，是模块，是出口，不是模块，是出口。
So yeah, module.exports,
not modules.exports.
Jason Lengstorf: 创建这个文件之后，我们就可以进入我们的 File 和
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: So with this created,
we can go into our File and
我们会把它包括进去的。
we'll just include that.
所以我们称之为默认值,
So withDefaults, we'll call it that,
我们只需要我们的 uils / default 选项。
and we'll just require our
utils/default-options.
所以我可以用我们需要的零件来替换这个 TODO,
And so I can replace this TODO
with just the pieces we need,
所以这次我们要用内容路径。
so we're gonna use
the contentPath this time.
我们会说 withDefaults (选项)。
And we'll say withDefaults(options).
所以我们要做的就是选择用户提供的选项,
And so what we're doing is we're
taking the user supplied options,
将其放入 withDefaults。
dropping it into withDefaults.
然后取出我们要用的那一块。
And then just extracting the one
piece that we're gonna use.
那么，一旦我们有了这个，我们就会知道我们在哪里,
So then, once we have that,
we're going to figure out where we are,
然后附加 contentPath。
and then append the contentPath to that.
为了弄清楚我们在哪里，我们将使用 path 模块。
So to figure out where we are,
we're going to use the path module.
So will require (‘ path’) ，然后我们可以设置我们的目录。
So will require('path') and
then we can set up our directory.
这就是 path.join 我们将使用这个程序,
And that is going to be path.join and
we'll use the program,
所以盖茨比的设置，拿到盖茨比运行的文件夹。
so Gatsby's setup,
get the folder where Gatsby is running.
然后我们将附加 contentPath。
And then we will append
the contentPath to that.
现在我们已经创建了一个目录，它是文件系统上的位置
So now we've created a directory that
is the location on the file system
内容应该存在的位置。
of where content should exist.